hey guys you've heard of the quadratic
formula it's a great way to solve ax^2 +
BX + Cal 0 but did you also know there
was a cubic formula if you want to solve
for a x Cub + bx2 + cx+ d = 0 x is going
to be equal to all of this stuff and
this is so long that it requires two
rows I thought it'd be fun to test this
out on X Cub is equal to 8 so first
let's copy down the formula and we need
to rewrite X Cub equal 8 in this format
First Step let's subtract 8 from both
sides and that gives us X Cub minus 8
equals 0 and let's give ourselves some
space so that we can include the 0 x^2
and the 0x and then this x Cub needs a
coefficient so let's give it a one and
now we're ready to use this formula I
think the zeros could help us simplify
this quite a bit so let's start with b
equals 0 in the place of all of these
B's let's plug in zero and then now
everywhere where there's a
multiplicative zero is just going to be
zero so this whole term can vanish so
you can see just by the fact that b was
Zero we were able to get rid of a lot of
these terms and then we can smush
everything everything together and we
can even move this up here next let's do
the other zero the C equals z so we can
change this C right here into zero and
this C right here into zero and both of
those are going to vanish as well next
let's focus on the a is equal to one so
we can plug in one for both of these A's
and we can plug in one for both of these
A's and all four of these denominators
are 2 * 1 so they're all just going to
become two and now we can focus on that
D it's equal to8 so all four of these
D's are going to be8 and now we can just
simplify things this negative and this
negative will cancel each other out and
8 / 2 is 4 this squared on the outside
will distribute to the top and the
bottom so we're going to have 8^ 2 and
2^2 the 82 is equal to POS 64 and 2^2 is
equal to 4 and then 64 / by 4 is 16 squ
< TK of 16 gives us 4 and 4 + 4 is equal
to 8 and then the cube root of 8 is
equal to 2 and now we can do the second
cube root the negative and negative will
cancel each other out 8 / 2 is 4 and
this squar will go to the top and bottom
and 8^2 is 64 and 2^2 is equal to 4 64 /
4 is 16 and the < TK of 16 is equal to 4
4 - 4 is equal to 0 and then the cube
root of 0 is just 0 so then we end up
with x = 2 + 0 which is just 2 so the
cubic formula gave us the real solution
to X Cub = 8 it's xal 2 let's put a box
around it how exciting